so how do we improve reliability and
availability we can try to avoid faults
which is about preventing folds from
occurring in the first place for example
the no coffee in the server room is one
example of a fault avoidance technique
if we spilled the coffee on a server
that's probably going to be a fault so
we're trying to avoid that fault by
preventing people from bringing coffee
into the server room next we can have a
fault tolerance technique there about
preventing faults from graduating in two
failures a typical fault tolerance
technique will use redundancy for
example ECC can be used for memory and
easy systems for error correcting code
so what happens is if there is a fault
for example a particle strike that flips
a bit in memory ECC will allow us to
read that blog from memory realize that
one of the bits has been flipped and
actually correct that bit and then we
can also have techniques like speeding
up the repair which really affect only
availability and an example of such a
technique is when we have a spare hard
drive in a drawer so when a hard drive
fails we can quickly replace it so this
is a technique where basically the
failure will still occur but we will
shorten the period that it takes to
repair the system by basically in this
case not having to wait for a new hard
drive to arrive we already have one
handy on site so we will now look more
closely at the fault tolerance
techniques which are usually techniques
that we can apply in computer
architecture to try to prevent Falls
from becoming failures and thus make
systems both more reliable and more
available